trafficforce.com 2019-03-26

# About this privacy policy

Last Updated: May 25th, 2018
This is the privacy policy for www.TrafficForce.com, “our site” and related
mobile applications.
We use your personal data for many reasons, from understanding how our users
engage with and use our site to making informed decisions about our marketing
and advertising.
These are the main reasons why we collect and use data about our users:
   •   To provide quality content;
   •   To provide the services you sign up for, such as subscriptions;
   •   To carry out marketing analysis and send you communications when we
       have your permission, or when permitted by law
   •   To enable us to show advertisements on our sites.
We think carefully about our use of personal data, and below you can find the
details of what we do to protect your privacy. This policy covers, among other
topics :
   •   Information about your rights and our obligations
   •   Clarity about our dealings with you and transparency about how we collect
       and use your personal data
   •   Commitments on how we protect your personal data
   •   Commitments on how we will facilitate your rights and respond to your
       questions.
We will continue to examine how we can provide more clarity to our users about
our use of data.
About this privacy policy
This privacy policy explains how we collect, use, share and transfer your personal
data when you use the services provided on by us.
Personal data is any information about you by which you can be identified. This
can include information such as:
   •   your name, date of birth, email address, postal address, phone number,
       mobile number;
   •   credit card and debit card details;

    •  information about your device (such as the IP address, which is a
       numerical code to identify your device that can provide information about
       the country, region or city where you are based); and
    •  information relating to your personal circumstances and how you use our
       sites, apps and services.
Sometimes our sites and apps may contain links to third party sites and services.
These sites and services have their own privacy policies. If you follow a link to a
third party, you should read the privacy policy shown on their site.
Who we are and how to contact us
The data controller for our sites and apps is GLP 5, LTD, Suite 9, Ansuya Estate,
Revolution Avenue, Victoria, Mahe, Seychelles. This means that we are
responsible for deciding how and why we hold and use your personal data. If you
want to contact us, you can find our contact details in the “How to contact us”
section below.
What personal data we collect and how we use it
We collect personal data when you sign up for our services and when you browse
our sites or use our apps. This information is used to provide our site and other
services, display advertising and analyze how visitors use our sites or apps.
The personal data we collect when you register for an account with our site.
    •  your email address;
    •  your username
    •  your photograph, if you add one to your profile page.
When you register for an account, we assign you a unique ID number that we use
to recognize you when you are signed in to use our services. This will recognize
you if you sign in using the same account on a new device or through a different
application.
When you use our sites or apps we may also use cookies or similar technology to
collect extra data, including:
    •  your IP address - a numerical code to identify your device and which can
       provide information about the country, region or city where you are based;
    •  your browsing history of the content you have visited on our sites,
       including information on how you were referred to our sites via another
       website; and
    •  details of your devices, for example, the unique device ID, unique
       advertising ID and browsers used to access our content.

Some of our services, may give you the option of providing more information
about your preferences, so that we can tailor your experience. Signing up for
membership may also mean you need to provide other details such as your
address details. Signing up to one of our affiliate programs will mean you need to
provide sufficient details such as a bank account number so that we can pay you.
We will not collect special categories of data - such as information about your
race, political opinions, religion, health or sexual orientation - unless you have
chosen to provide that information to us.
Posting comments on our sites
When you post information on a discussion board or comment publicly on an
article on one of our sites, the information you post and your username are
publicly accessible. This information can be viewed online and collected by other
people. We are not responsible for the way these other people use this
information. When contributing to a discussion, we strongly recommend you
avoid sharing any personal details, and especially information that can be used to
identify you directly such as your name, age, address and name of employer. We
are not responsible for the privacy of any identifiable information that you post in
our online community or other public pages of the site.
Using our apps
Our app uses information on the content you have viewed. You can delete this
history in the settings of the app. Information on what you have viewed in the
app and information on bugs and crashes is also sent to us. You can choose to
receive notifications on your mobile device via the app. You can manage these
notifications in the settings of the app.
How we collect personal data
We collect personal data when you:
   •   register an account on our site;
   •   register as a webmaster with our affiliate program;
   •   submit a domain to our parking platform;
   •   pay for a membership;
   •   enter our competitions and surveys;
   •   sign up to our email list;
   •   post in our online community;
   •   sign up for marketing communications;
   •   use mobile devices to access our content;

   • access our sites, through cookies and other similar technology; and
   • when you contact us via email, social media, our apps or similar
     technologies or when you mention us on social media.
Why we use your personal data
We use personal data collected through our sites and apps for a number of
purposes, including the following:
   • To provide the services you sign up for. We also use the personal data for
     related internal administrative purposes - such as our accounting and
     records - and to make you aware of any changes to our services.
   • To send marketing communications when we have your permission, or
     when permitted by law.
   • To personalize our services (for example, so you can sign in), remembering
     your settings, displaying personalized advertising as well as measuring how
     effective our online adverts are, recognizing you when you sign in on
     different devices and tailoring our marketing communications based on
     what you view on our site.
   • To carry out marketing analysis, for example we look at what you have
     viewed on our sites and apps and what products and services you have
     bought (including what you have looked at and what products or services
     you have bought on our other platforms) to better understand what your
     interests and preferences are, and to improve our marketing by making it
     more relevant to your interests and preferences. You can opt out from
     having your personal data used for marketing analysis by emailing
     dpo@trafficforce.com.
   • To improve our marketing communications, we use a similar technology to
     cookies to confirm whether you have opened a marketing email or clicked
     on a link in the email.
   • To sell advertising space on our sites.
   • For statistical purposes such as analyzing the performance of our sites and
     apps and to understand how visitors use them.
   • To respond to your queries and to resolve complaints.
   • For security and fraud prevention, and to ensure that our sites and apps
     are safe and secure and used in line with our terms of use.
   • To comply with applicable laws and regulations.

Access permissions that we ask from users of Our app
When you use our app, we ask for the following permissions to access particular
functions of your mobile device:
    • For the Android version, we ask for permission to access your contact
      details/profile on your mobile device, so that we can add or find your
      Account on your phone.
    • For the iOS version, we ask for permission to save pictures to your photo
      library, so that you can save pictures that you find in our articles on your
      mobile device.
Legal grounds for using your personal data
We will only use your personal data where we have a legal ground to do so. We
determine the legal grounds based on the purposes for which we have collected
and used your personal data. In every case, the legal ground will be one of the
following:
    • Consent: For example, where you have provided your consent to receive
      marketing emails from us. You can withdraw your consent at any time. In
      the case of marketing emails you can withdraw your consent by clicking on
      the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of the email or through your email
      preferences in the “emails and marketing” tab, when signed into your
      Account.
    • Our legitimate interests: Where it is necessary for us to understand our
      users, promote our services and operate our sites and apps efficiently for
      the creation, publication and distribution of news, media and related
      content both online and in print form, globally. For example, we will rely
      on our legitimate interest when we analyze what content has been viewed
      on our sites and apps, so that we can understand how they are used. It is
      also in our legitimate interest to carry out marketing analysis to determine
      what products and services may be relevant to the interests of our readers.
      You can opt out from having your personal data used for marketing
      analysis by emailing dpo@trafficforce.com.
    • Performance of a contract with you (or in order to take steps prior to
      entering into a contract with you): For example, where you have purchased
      a membership from us and we need to use your contact details and
      payment information in order to process your order, or you have signed up
      to our affiliate program or hosted tube program and we needed to use your
      personal information to pay you.
    • Compliance with law: In some cases, we may have a legal obligation to use
      or keep your personal data.

Updating your personal data and your profile page on our sites
When you register for an account with our site, you may have access to a profile
page. Under “edit profile” you can review what information is public when you
comment on our content, or if people look up your profile. You can also update
your information or provide extra information if you want.
Personal data that we receive about you from
other organizations
Adding to or combining the personal data you provide to us
When you sign up for our services we may add to the personal data you give us by
combining it with information shared with us by other trusted organizations. This
includes, for example, information about the region that you are located in, so
that we can show you the prices for memberships or other products in your local
currency. We may also obtain information from partners whose offers we include
in some of our marketing communications and we use this information to ensure
that we do not send you irrelevant marketing.
We also use information on the content you have viewed on our sites and apps
and your interaction with the content to add you to groups with similar interests
and preferences, so that we can make our online advertising more relevant.
Sometimes we use data about your interests or demographics that third parties
have collected from you online to add to these groups. Please refer to our cookies
policy (located at the end of this document) for more information on how we use
cookies.
Data for persons under 18
This Website is not intended for minors. You will only access the Website or
register if you are at least 18-years old and have reached the age of majority in the
country where you live if that age happens to be greater than 18. We prohibit all
persons who do not meet the age requirements from accessing the Website.
Minors will not access the Website or use its services.
We do not knowingly collect any information about children, minors, or anyone
under the age of majority. Nor do we knowingly market to children, minors, or
anyone under 18-years old. If you are under 18-years old, we ask that you do not
submit information to us. If we become aware that a child, minor, or anyone
under 18-years old has registered with us and provided us with personal
information, we will take steps to cancel that person’s registration. If we do
cancel a registration because you breached our no children rules, we may keep
your email and IP address to make sure that you do not try to get around our
rules by creating a new account.
In accordance with 47 U.S.C. § 230(d), we notify you that parental control
protections (including computer hardware, software, or filtering services) are

commercially available that may assist in limiting access to material that is
harmful to minors. You may find information about providers of these
protections on the Internet by searching “parental control protection” or similar
terms. If minors have access to your computer, please restrain their access to
sexually explicit material by using any of the following products, which we
provide for informational purposes only and do not endorse: CYBERsitter™ | Net
Nanny® | CyberPatrol | ASACP.
Security of your personal data
We have implemented appropriate technical and organizational controls to
protect your personal data against unauthorized processing and against
accidental loss, damage or destruction. You are responsible for choosing a secure
password when we ask you to set up a password to access parts of our sites or
apps. You should keep this password confidential and you should choose a
password that you do not use on any other site. You should not share your
password with anyone else, including anyone who works for us. Unfortunately,
sending information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will
do our best to protect your personal data once with us, we cannot guarantee the
security of any personal data sent to our site while still in transit and so you
provide it at your own risk.
Who we share your personal data with
We do not share your personal data with other people or organizations that are
not directly linked or affiliated to us except under the following circumstances:
   •  To contractors, service providers and other third parties we use to support
      our business and who are bound by contractual obligations to keep
      personal information confidential and use it only for the purposes for
      which we disclose it to them.
   •  To a buyer or other successor in the event of a merger, divestiture,
      restructuring, reorganization, dissolution, or other sale or transfer of some
      or all of our assets, whether as a going concern or as part of bankruptcy,
      liquidation, or similar proceeding, in which personal information held by
      us about our Website users is among the assets transferred.
   •  To fulfill the purpose for which you provide it.
   •  For any other purpose disclosed by us when you provide the information.
   •  We may share your data with other organizations that provide services on
      our behalf such as dealing with online payments and other forms of
      payment processing, i.e. credit card transactions, online bank payments
      and preventing fraud.

    •  We may also share your data with our advertising partners, as set out in the
       section about Online Advertising below.
    •  We may reveal your personal data to any law enforcement agency, court,
       regulator, government authority or other organization if we are required to
       do so to meet a legal or regulatory obligation, or otherwise to protect our
       rights or the rights of anyone else.
    •  We may reveal your personal data to any other organization that buys, or to
       which we transfer all, or substantially all, of our assets and business. If this
       sale or transfer takes place, we will use reasonable efforts to try to make
       sure that the organization we transfer your personal data to uses it in line
       with our privacy policy.
Any organizations which access your data in the course of providing services on
our behalf will be governed by strict contractual restrictions to make sure that
they protect your data and keep to all data privacy laws that apply. We may also
independently audit these service providers to make sure that they meet our
standards.
We will not share your personal data with anyone else for their own marketing
purposes unless we have your permission to do this.
Some of our webpages use social plug-ins from other organizations (such as the
“Facebook Recommend” function, Twitter’s retweet function, Google+ function).
These other organizations may receive and use personal data about your visit to
our sites or apps. If you browse our site or view content on our apps, information
they collect may be connected to your account on their site. For more information
on how these organizations use personal data, please read their privacy policies.
Third Party-Payment Processors
All transactions which are processed are subject to our third-party payment
processor’s privacy policies. Before purchasing items or services on our site and
before providing any personally identifiable information to any of our third-party
payment processors you should inform yourself of the privacy policies and
practices (if any) of the third-party payment processors responsible for
processing your transaction, and should take those steps necessary to, in your
discretion, protect your privacy. The privacy policies of our third-party payment
processors shall be incorporated into this Privacy Policy by reference. You also
agree that it is necessary for both us and any third-party payment processor to
maintain a record of all transactions processed on this website.
International data transfers

Data we collect may be transferred to, stored and processed in any country or
territory where one or more of our affiliates or service providers are based or
have facilities. While other countries or territories may not have the same
standards of data protection as those in your home country, we will continue to
protect personal data that we transfer in line with this privacy policy.
Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the European Economic Area
(EEA), we ensure similar protection and put in place at least one of these
safeguards:
    •  We will only transfer your personal data to countries that have been found
       to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data.
    •  We may also use specific approved contracts with our service providers
       that are based in countries outside the EEA. These contracts give your
       personal data the same protection it has in the EEA .
    •  Where we use service providers in the United States, we may transfer
       personal data to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield scheme, which
       requires them to provide a similar level of protection of your personal data
       to what is required in the EEA.
If you are located in the EEA, you may contact us for a copy of the safeguards
which we have put in place for the transfer of your personal data outside the EEA.
How long we keep your personal data
We keep your personal data for only as long as we need to. How long we need
your personal data depends on what we are using it for, as set out in this privacy
policy. For example, we may need to use it to answer your queries about a
products or service and as a result may keep personal data while you are still
using our product or services. We may also need to keep your personal data for
accounting purposes, for example, where you have bought a membership. If we
no longer need your data, we will delete it or make it anonymous by removing all
details that identify you. If we have asked for your permission to process your
personal data and we have no other lawful grounds to continue with that
processing, and you withdraw your permission, we will delete your personal data.
However, when you unsubscribe from marketing communications, we will keep
your email address to ensure that we do not send you any marketing in future.
How we may contact you
Service communications
From time to time we may send you service emails, for example, telling you your
membership is coming to an end or thanking you when you contribute or place
an order with us.

Marketing communications and editorial newsletters
If we have your permission, we may send you materials we think may interest
you, such as offers and updates. Depending on your marketing preferences, this
may be by email, phone, SMS or post.
You can decide not to receive these emails at any time and will be able to
“unsubscribe” directly by clicking a link in the email or by emailing
dpo@trafficforce.com.
Responding to your queries or complaints
If you have raised a query or a complaint with us, we may contact you to answer
your query or to resolve your complaint.
Cookies and similar technology
When you visit our sites or when you use our apps, we may collect personal data
from you automatically using cookies or similar technology. A cookie is a small
file that can be placed on your device that allows us to recognize and remember
you.
This privacy policy includes our cookies policy, (located at the end of this
document), where you can find details of our key advertising partners.
Online advertising
Advertising on our sites that is based on cookies and similar technology
We use personalized online advertising on our sites. This allows us to deliver
more relevant advertising to people who visit our site. It works by showing you
adverts that are based on your browsing patterns and the way you have interacted
with our sites and apps. It then shows you adverts which we believe may interest
you.
When you browse our sites or use our apps, some of the cookies and similar
technology we place on your device are advertising cookies, so we can understand
what sort of pages you are interested in. We can then display advertising on your
browser based on these interests.
We do not collect or use information such as your name, email address, postal
address or phone number for personalized online advertising.
We may also share online data collected through cookies and similar technology
with our advertising partners. This means that when you are on another website,
you may be shown advertising based on your browsing patterns on our site. We
may also show you advertising on our site based on your browsing patterns on
other sites that we have obtained from our advertising partners.

Online retargeting is another form of online advertising that allows us and some
of our advertising partners to show you advertising based on your browsing
patterns and interactions with a site away from our sites.
For example, if you have visited the website of an online clothes shop, you may
start seeing adverts from that same shopping site displaying special offers or
showing you products you were browsing. This allows companies to advertise to
you if you leave their website without making a purchase.
Advertising that we place on our site or on other
sites
We also use personalized online advertising to promote our own products and
services. This means that you may see advertising for our products and services
on our sites and when you are on other, third party websites, including social
media platforms.
Your rights with regard to the personal data that
we hold about you
You can contact us with regard to the following rights in relation to your personal
data:
    •  If you would like to have a copy of the personal data we hold on you or if
       you think that we hold incorrect personal data about you, please write to
       the Data Protection Officer at dpo@trafficforce.com. We will deal with
       requests for copies of your personal data or for correction of your personal
       data within one month. If your request is complicated or if you have made
       a large number of requests, it may take us longer. We will let you know if
       we need longer than one month to respond. You will not have to pay a fee
       to obtain a copy of your personal data (or to exercise any of the other
       rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly
       unfounded, repetitive or excessive.
    •  Where you have provided us with consent to use your personal data, you
       can withdraw this at any time.
    •  Where applicable, you may also have a right to receive a machine-readable
       copy of your personal data.
    •  You also have the right to ask us to delete your personal data or restrict
       how it is used. There may be exceptions to the right to erasure for specific
       legal reasons which, if applicable, we will set out for you in response to
       your request. Where applicable, you have the right to object to processing
       of your personal data for certain purposes.

    •  If you do not want us to use your personal data for marketing analysis, you
       can do so by emailing dpo@trafficforce.com.
If you want to make any of these requests, please contact dpo@trafficforce.com.
We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your
identity.
Your California privacy rights
Under California Civil Code Section 1798.83, if you live in California and your
business relationship with us is mainly for personal, family or household
purposes, you may ask us about the information we release to other organizations
for their marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an email
to dpo@trafficforce.com with “Request for California privacy information” in the
subject line. You may make this type of request once every calendar year. We will
email you a list of categories of personal data we revealed to other organizations
for their marketing purposes in the last calendar year, along with their names and
addresses. Not all personal data shared in this way is covered by Section 1798.83
of the California Civil Code.
Canada Privacy Rights
We comply with Canadian Federal and Provincial privacy laws and regulations
including the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act.
We will only use your personal information for the purposes intended and as
detailed in this privacy policy unless we have obtained your consent to use it for
other purposes.
Residents of Canada are notified that the personal information they provide to us
is stored in our databases outside of Canada including in the United States and
may be subject to disclosure to authorized law enforcement or government
agencies in response to lawful demand under the laws of that country.
If you need to contact us about your personal information or believe that we have
violated your privacy rights, please email us at dpo@trafficforce.com. You may visit
www.priv.gc.ca for more information about your privacy rights.
Contact us for information about how we use your
personal data
If you have any questions about how we use your personal data or if you have a
concern about how your personal data is used, please contact the Data Protection
Officer at dpo@trafficforce.com.
Complaints will be dealt with by the Data Protection Officer and will be
responded to within 30 days.

If you are not satisfied with the way your concern has been handled, you can refer
your complaint to the Information Commissioner’s Office.
If you have a question about anything else, please contact us
gsc@trafficforce.com.
Changes to the Privacy Policy
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post the changes here. If
required by law, we will get your permission or give you the opportunity to opt
out of any new uses of your data.
Cookie Policy
What is a cookie?
A cookie is a small file that can be placed on your device that allows us to
recognize and remember you. It is sent to your browser and stored on your
computer’s hard drive or tablet or mobile device. When you visit our sites, we
may collect information from you automatically through cookies or similar
technology.
How do we use cookies?
We use cookies in a range of ways to improve your experience on our site,
including
    •  Keeping you signed in
    •  Understanding how you use our site
    •  Showing you media that is relevant to you
    •  Showing you products and services that are relevant to you
    •  Working with partners to serve you relevant advertising
Ultimately, this allows us to publish media you view on our sites and apps.
In the next section, we explain in more detail how we use cookies and similar
technology on our sites and apps for a number of purposes.
Other organizations also collect user information on our sites through cookies,
tags and pixels. Tags and pixels, also known as web beacons, are similar to
cookies but are collected through embedded images.
Using cookies and other technology allows other organizations to help us to
analyze how our site is being used, measure the number of visitors to the site, and
for display advertising.

Cookies that are used by us are referred to as “first-party cookies” and those that
are used by our partners are “third-party cookies”. Because of how cookies work,
our website cannot access third-party cookies; nor can other organizations access
the data in the cookies we use on our website. There are more details about both
in the following sections.
What types of cookies do we use ?
We use four types of cookies, which we describe in this section.
    •  Essential – cookies that are essential to provide you with services you have
       requested. For example, these include the cookies that make it possible for
       you to stay logged into your account and make comments. If you set your
       browser to block these cookies, then these functions and services will not
       work for you. In particular, we won’t be able to save your preferences about
       cookies.
    •  Performance - cookies which measure how often you visit our sites and
       how you use them. We use this information to get a better sense of how our
       users engage with our content and to improve our sites and apps, so that
       users have a better experience. For example, we collect information about
       which of our pages are most frequently visited, and by which types of users.
       We also use third-party cookies to help with performance. For example, the
       Google Analytics cookie gives us information such as your journey between
       pages and whether you have downloaded anything (details of how to opt
       out of it are below).
    •  Functionality – cookies that are used to recognize you and remember your
       preferences or settings when you return to our site, so that we can provide
       you with a more personalized experience. A mix of first-party and third-
       party cookies are used.
    •  Advertising – cookies that are used to collect information about your visit
       to our site, the content you have viewed, the links you have followed and
       information about your browser, device and your IP address. We have set
       out more details on this below.
How do we use cookies for advertising?
Cookies are a key part of how we deliver advertising on our sites. Among other
uses, they allow us to show more relevant advertising to people who visit our site
by showing you adverts that are based on your browsing patterns and the way
you have interacted with our sites and apps. We can then show you adverts which
we believe may interest you.
As you browse our site, some of the cookies and similar technology we place on
your device are for advertising, so we can understand what sorts of pages you

read and are interested in. We can then display advertising on your browser
based on these interests.
The advertising techniques we use do not collect information such as your name,
email address, postal address or phone number. We sometimes use information
such as your IP address and browser type and also sometimes share some limited
aspects of this with third parties for advertising purposes.
We may also share online data collected through cookies and similar technology
with our advertising partners. This means that when you are on another website,
you may be shown advertising based on your browsing patterns on our site. We
may also show you advertising on our site based on your browsing patterns on
other sites that we have obtained from our advertising partners.
Online retargeting is another form of online advertising that allows us and some
of our advertising partners to show you advertising based on your browsing
patterns and interactions with other sites. The use of cookies may mean that
when you are on another site, you may be shown advertising based on what you
have looked at on our site.
Our App integrates third-party software that provides us with information about
how the app is used and what content you have viewed for the purposes of online
advertising and analytics, in a similar way to the sites. It uses cookies from some
of the providers listed here, among others.
How to manage advertising cookies
You can manage the use of cookies, including advertising cookies, and disable the
sharing of data with partners for advertising purposes by using the steps set out
here. In some cases you can turn off advertising cookies on a cookie-by-cookie
basis, and we give the most common examples below.
You can switch some cookies off through the Your Online Choices site. You may
need to do this again each time you use a different IP address or device.
It is also possible to stop your browser from accepting cookies altogether by
changing your browser’s cookie settings. You can usually find these settings in the
“options” or “preferences” menu of your browser. The following links may be
helpful, or you can use the “Help” option in your browser.
    •   Cookie settings in Internet Explorer
    •   Cookie settings in Firefox
    •   Cookie settings in Chrome
    •   Cookie settings in Safari web and iOS
Useful links

If you would like to find out more about privacy, cookies and their use on the
internet, you may find the following links useful:
    •  Microsoft cookies guide
    •  All About Cookies
    •  The Information Commissioner’s Office
If you would like to contact us about cookies please email dpo@trafficforce.com
